

IOS DEVELOPER

Details

18521300012

yang.weicheng.coder@gmail.com

Links

github.com/Andy1984

Skills

Objective C

Swift

Git

Video Processing

iOS Reverse Engineering

Profile

Professional iOS Developer with 5 years of experience and a zest for solving complex problems. Developed a total of 8 mobile applications. Continuously discovers, evaluates, and implements new technologies and methodologies to optimize applications and software.

Education

Bachelor of Business Administration, Shanghai Ocean University

SEPTEMBER 2009 - JUNE 2013

Employment History

iOS Developer, Ping An Bank, lu.com, Shanghai, China

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

- Planned, developed, tested, and maintained iOS applications.
- Took over video playing. Fixed serious online bugs within a week, including black screen, UI lag, and memory leaks. Developed preloading and cache function to improve user experience. Encapsulated and modularized video player and provided it to the H5 team
- Imported Swift framework 'Charts' into the Objective-C project to create highly complicated bar charts, pie charts, and scatter charts.

Working Holiday Maker, Cairns, Australia

APRIL 2018 - APRIL 2019

I applied for a working holiday visa and traveled around Australia. I can find a job if I need money. Most of the time, I was a night auditor in a three-star hotel.

iOS Developer, YI Technology, Shanghai, China

NOVEMBER 2014 - MARCH 2018

- Built YI Action Camera app from scratch. Revised and maintained the project for more than three years. YI Action Camera is an alternative to GoPro.
- Developed UGC (User Generated Content) Community, which is similar to Instagram.
- Used FFmpeg to add stickers to video, and AVFoundation to trim video, audio and blend them.
- Supported YI Mirrorless team twice to expedite the lagging behind project.

Github Projects

AORangeSlider

AORangeSlider is a custom UISlider with two handlers to pick a minimum and a maximum range.

YWCLocalizeTool

Used Baidu Translator API to help developers translate their app into different lanauages.

huahuaWHV

huahuaWHV is a wechat mini program written in Javascript. Used leanCloud as Backend-as-a-Service. Working holiday makers can fill out a form to get an address and receive their tax file numbers. When files are received, administrators can update the information in leanCloud and users can see their tax file numbers.